Thank you so much everyone. I'm really happy to be here.
ขอบคุณมากครับทุกคน ผมดีใจมากที่ได้มาอยู่ที่นี่
And today I would like to talk about how I use Supabase in a real world
วันนี้ผมอยากจะมาพูดคุยเกี่ยวกับการที่ผมใช้ Supabase ในโปรเจกต์
project in something that we're not going to be talking about the theory.
จริงๆ ไม่ใช่แค่ทฤษฎี
Instead, we're going to be talking about practice.
แต่เราจะมาพูดถึงการใช้งานจริง
And I've been a full stack developer working mostly on CRMs and AI systems
ผมเป็น full stack developer ทำงานส่วนใหญ่เกี่ยวกับ CRM และ AI systems
for UK and Israel, and I also contribute to open source a lot.
ให้กับบริษัทใน UK และ Israel และผมก็ contribute โอเพ่นซอร์สเยอะมาก
For example, there is a front end library
ยกตัวอย่างเช่น มี front-end library
that is quite popular on GitHub. It has 27,000 stars on GitHub
ที่ค่อนข้างเป็นที่นิยมบน GitHub มี 27,000 ดาวบน GitHub
and more than 6 million downloads each month.
และมีคนดาวน์โหลดมากกว่า 6 ล้านครั้งต่อเดือน
And you can find me in the list of the top contributors.
และคุณสามารถหาผมเจอในรายชื่อ top contributors
So a few months ago, I decided to switch completely
เมื่อไม่กี่เดือนที่ผ่านมา ผมตัดสินใจเปลี่ยน
to bootstrapping my own project. I do believe that every developer
ไปทำโปรเจกต์ของตัวเอง ผมเชื่อว่านักพัฒนา
should try at least once in a lifetime to build his own project,
ทุกคนควรลองสร้างโปรเจกต์ของตัวเองอย่างน้อยหนึ่งครั้งในชีวิต
because it allows to see the bigger picture.
เพราะมันจะทำให้คุณเห็นภาพรวมมากขึ้น
It allows you to see beyond the code to understand better business needs.
มันจะทำให้คุณเห็นอะไรที่มากกว่าโค้ด เพื่อทำความเข้าใจความต้องการทางธุรกิจได้ดีขึ้น
And I do believe that Supabase is a really great platform for that,
และผมเชื่อว่า Supabase เป็นแพลตฟอร์มที่ดีมากสำหรับสิ่งนั้น
because it can basically replace a team of, I don't know, like back
เพราะมันสามารถแทนที่ทีม back-end engineers
end engineers, DevOps engineers, some kind of database engineers.
DevOps engineers และ database engineers ได้
So you can have everything in one platform and run project
คุณสามารถมีทุกอย่างในแพลตฟอร์มเดียว และรันโปรเจกต์
just by your own. And in this talk I'm first briefly
ได้ด้วยตัวคุณเอง ในหัวข้อนี้ ผมจะพูดถึง
I'm going to talk about the project. So you get the context.
โปรเจกต์คร่าวๆ เพื่อให้คุณเข้าใจบริบท
And then we switch to Supabase features that I find very useful.
จากนั้นเราจะเปลี่ยนไปพูดถึงฟีเจอร์ของ Supabase ที่ผมคิดว่ามีประโยชน์
And I do believe that you will find them useful too.
และผมเชื่อว่าคุณก็จะคิดว่ามันมีประโยชน์เช่นกัน
So just to get you the basic idea. Currently the it is database
เพื่อให้คุณเข้าใจพื้นฐาน ตอนนี้
Supabase dashboard that shows that it has like 10,000 database
Supabase dashboard แสดงให้เห็นว่ามีประมาณ 10,000 database
requests per day, and it has around 6000 monthly active users.
requests ต่อวัน และมีประมาณ 6,000 monthly active users
And so you can understand that is a project that is being used
ดังนั้นคุณจะเข้าใจได้ว่าเป็นโปรเจกต์ที่ถูกใช้งาน
by real users. And let's talk about the project
โดยผู้ใช้จริง และเรามาพูดถึงโปรเจกต์
first very briefly. Like do you know that like 60%
คร่าวๆ ก่อน คุณรู้ไหมว่า 60%
of information that we get gets forgotten in an hour and in one
ของข้อมูลที่เราได้รับ จะถูกลืมภายในหนึ่งชั่วโมง
week, only 10% of information remains.
และในหนึ่งสัปดาห์ เราจะจำมันได้เพียงแค่ 10% เท่านั้น
This rule was discovered by German scientist Hermann Ebbinghaus.
กฎนี้ถูกค้นพบโดยนักวิทยาศาสตร์ชาวเยอรมัน Hermann Ebbinghaus
And actually, it's quite good because, like,
จริงๆ แล้วมันก็ค่อนข้างดี เพราะ
we don't need to keep everything that happened to us in our brain.
เราไม่จำเป็นต้องเก็บทุกอย่างที่เกิดขึ้นกับเราไว้ในสมอง
But in case you study a language or music theory or history, you would
แต่ในกรณีที่คุณเรียนภาษา ทฤษฎีดนตรี หรือประวัติศาสตร์ คุณ
like information that you already learned to persist in your brain.
ต้องการให้ข้อมูลที่คุณเรียนรู้คงอยู่ในสมองของคุณ
So to achieve that, you need to repeat the information and you don't
เพื่อให้บรรลุเป้าหมายนั้น คุณต้องทบทวนความจำ และคุณไม่
have to repeat Information every day. Instead, you can use the spaced
จำเป็นต้องทบทวนความจำเหล่านั้นทุกวัน แต่คุณสามารถใช้
repetition approach. For example, you can repeat
เทคนิค spaced repetition แทนได้ ตัวอย่างเช่น คุณสามารถทบทวน
information on the first day, then on the third day, then on the
ข้อมูลในวันแรก จากนั้นในวันที่สาม จากนั้นใน
sixth day, then 25, and so on. So the idea is that you don't
วันที่หก จากนั้น 25 และอื่นๆ แนวคิดคือคุณไม่
need to spend a lot of time repeating information.
จำเป็นต้องใช้เวลามากในการทบทวนข้อมูลซ้ำๆ
So you can spend less time but still be like but still
คุณสามารถใช้เวลาน้อยลง แต่ยังคง
effectively memorize everything. And this is what the application I
จดจำทุกอย่างได้อย่างมีประสิทธิภาพ และผมสร้างแอปพลิเคชัน
built based on. So simple example. You study English language and
โดยอิงตามพื้นฐานนี้ ตัวอย่างง่ายๆ คุณเรียนภาษาอังกฤษ
you want to remember the phrase get ahead.
และคุณต้องการจำวลี “get ahead”
So you add a card with this information.
คุณเพิ่มการ์ดที่มีข้อมูลนี้
And if you answer it correctly then the app automatically schedules all
และถ้าคุณตอบถูก แอปจะกำหนดเวลา
the this word to repeat in one day, in three days, in six days,
ให้ทบทวนคำนี้ในหนึ่งวัน สามวัน หกวัน
and so on and so on. But if you fail to repeat,
ฯลฯ แต่ถ้าคุณทบทวนไม่สำเร็จ
you don't remember Then the intervals are shorter. And then you get
คุณจำไม่ได้ ช่วงเวลาจะสั้นลง และคุณจะได้รับ
smart notifications. So all of it is built using Supabase.
การแจ้งเตือนอัจฉริยะ ทั้งหมดนี้สร้างขึ้นโดยใช้ Supabase
And how it all started. First you need to create a lot of
และมันเริ่มต้นอย่างไร ก่อนอื่นคุณต้องสร้าง
tables, and Supabase provides the most, let's say user friendly way
ตารางจำนวนมาก และ Supabase มีวิธีที่
to scaffold the database schema. You just use graphical interface
ใช้งานง่ายที่สุดในการสร้าง database schema คุณเพียงแค่ใช้
to create all of your tables. For example, in my case I have tables
GUI ในการสร้างตารางทั้งหมดของคุณ ตัวอย่างเช่น ในกรณีของผม ผมมีตาราง
with users. Each user has many decks. A deck is like a group of cards.
สำหรับ users, แต่ละ user มีหลาย decks, deck ก็เหมือนกลุ่มของการ์ด
Then each deck has a lot of cards and each card has a lot of reviews.
จากนั้นแต่ละ deck มีการ์ดจำนวนมาก และแต่ละการ์ดมี review จำนวนมาก
So the same card can be reused multiple times by the same user
ดังนั้นการ์ดเดียวกันสามารถนำกลับมาใช้ใหม่ได้หลายครั้งโดย user เดียวกัน
or by another one. And once you finish,
หรือโดย user คนอื่น และเมื่อคุณเสร็จสิ้น
you are ready to basically to export it into a real database
คุณพร้อมที่จะ export มันไปยัง database จริง
that is available to the internet. So you just create something on
ที่สามารถเข้าถึงได้ทางอินเทอร์เน็ต คุณเพียงแค่สร้างบางอย่างบน
the internet, and then Supabase allows you to convert it to a
อินเทอร์เน็ต จากนั้น Supabase จะช่วยให้คุณแปลงเป็น
database that you can use in your code that is publicly available.
database ที่คุณสามารถใช้ในโค้ดของคุณที่สามารถเข้าถึงได้แบบสาธารณะ
And how to use it. So you have a basic SDK.
และวิธีการใช้งาน คุณมี SDK พื้นฐาน
I'm going to show examples in JavaScript, but you can use any
ผมจะแสดงตัวอย่างใน JavaScript แต่คุณสามารถใช้
language you want. And here we just need to access
ภาษาใดก็ได้ที่คุณต้องการ และที่นี่เราแค่ต้องเข้าถึง
Supabase. We specify the table, then the
Supabase เราระบุตาราง จากนั้น
operation if you want to query something or create a new record.
การดำเนินการ ถ้าคุณต้องการ query บางอย่าง หรือสร้าง record ใหม่
So we specify all the fields and then we specify what to select.
เราระบุฟิลด์ทั้งหมด จากนั้นเราระบุสิ่งที่ต้องการเลือก
A really nice feature that I enjoy is that Supabase allows you to
ฟีเจอร์ที่ดีจริงๆ ที่ผมชอบคือ Supabase ช่วยให้คุณ
generate all of your types in code. So basically you don't have to
สร้าง type ทั้งหมดใน DB คุณให้ ดังนั้นคุณไม่จำเป็นต้อง
transfer manually all of the tables, all of the fields to your code.
เขียน type ให้ตารางและฟิลด์ทั้งหมดในโค้ดของคุณด้วยตนเอง
Instead you run one Supabase command and you get all of this
คุณเพียงแค่รันคำสั่ง supabase คำสั่งเดียว และคุณจะได้รับ
structure in your code. So in my case, for like an
โครงสร้างทั้งหมดนี้ในโค้ดของคุณ ดังนั้นในกรณีของผม สำหรับ
application that has a lot of users, Supabase generates me around
แอปพลิเคชันที่มี users จำนวนมาก Supabase สร้างโค้ดให้ผมประมาณ
2000 lines of code and it keeps them automatically updated.
2,000 บรรทัด และมันจะอัปเดตโดยอัตโนมัติ
So let's say I decided to remove some field or rename some field.
สมมติว่าผมตัดสินใจลบฟิลด์บางฟิลด์ หรือเปลี่ยนชื่อฟิลด์บางฟิลด์
Once I done this in the database, I, I can just run the command.
เมื่อผมทำสิ่งนี้ใน database ผมสามารถรันคำสั่งได้
And then these fields gets removed from this schema.
และฟิลด์เหล่านี้จะถูกลบออกจาก schema นี้
And thanks to TypeScript, it can point me to the part of
และขอบคุณ TypeScript มันสามารถชี้ให้ผมเห็นส่วนของ
code where these fields were used. And you get TypeScript
โค้ดที่ใช้ฟิลด์เหล่านี้ มันจะแจ้งเตือน
compilation error. So until you fix all those issues,
ข้อผิดพลาดในการคอมไพล์ TypeScript ดังนั้นจนกว่าคุณจะแก้ไขปัญหาเหล่านั้นทั้งหมด
you won't be able to compile your project.
คุณจะไม่สามารถคอมไพล์โปรเจกต์ของคุณได้
And I believe it's very nice since it allows you to iterate faster.
และผมเชื่อว่ามันดีมาก เพราะมันช่วยให้คุณพัฒนาอย่างต่อเนื่องได้เร็วขึ้น
It allows you to do less bugs in production.
มันช่วยให้คุณมี bugs น้อยลงใน production
So this feature I use a lot. One of the decisive way for me to
ผมใช้ฟีเจอร์นี้บ่อยมาก หนึ่งในเหตุผลหลักที่ทำให้ผม
choose something like Supabase over, like something like Firebase is the
เลือก Supabase แทน Firebase คือ
idea is that I can write my own SQL query, and the SQL relational data
ผมสามารถเขียน SQL query ของตัวเองได้ และข้อมูลเชิงสัมพันธ์ของ SQL
is already optimized for all the, let's say, queries.
ได้รับการ optimize ให้เหมาะสมกับ query ทั้งหมดแล้ว
All the combinations of data that you may want to use.
การรวมกันของข้อมูลทั้งหมดที่คุณอาจต้องการใช้
The data is already stored in that way that you can run some
ข้อมูลถูกจัดเก็บในลักษณะที่คุณสามารถรัน
analytical queries, queries, and they're going to be like
analytical query ได้ และมันจะ
it's very easy to implement. So for that you can go to Supabase
ง่ายมากในการ implement คุณสามารถไปที่
dashboard and then select SQL editor. And for example write a SQL
dashboard ของ Supabase และเลือก SQL editor
query that groups all the users by by the language.
ตัวอย่างเช่น เขียน SQL query ที่จัดกลุ่ม users ทั้งหมดตามภาษา
So and here is going to be the result.
และนี่คือผลลัพธ์
You can see the amount of users and then the percent percentage.
คุณสามารถเห็นจำนวน users และเปอร์เซ็นต์
It's something like that PostgreSQL allows to do. It's called window.
มันเป็นสิ่งที่ PostgreSQL อนุญาตให้ทำ เรียกว่า
Window function. And you can use it for advanced
window function และคุณสามารถใช้มันสำหรับ
analytical queries. It is something that I really miss
analytical query ขั้นสูง มันเป็นสิ่งที่ไม่ค่อยมีให้ใช้
in NoSQL database for example. Moreover, you can of course use
ใน NoSQL database ยิ่งไปกว่านั้น คุณสามารถใช้
I to generate query for you in case you think like okay, why?
AI เพื่อสร้าง query ให้คุณ ในกรณีที่คุณคิดว่า ทำไม
Why should I bother myself doing that? Let's I do the job.
ทำไมผมต้องเสียเวลากับการทำแบบนั้น ให้ AI ทำงานแทน
So here I show how to do that. So I ask, I show me the number of
ผมจะแสดงวิธีการให้ดู ผมถามว่า แสดงจำนวน
active users for the last month, and I specify that active is
active users ในเดือนที่แล้ว และผมระบุว่า active คือ
someone who has. So who has logged in within the
คนที่ล็อกอินภายในเดือนปัจจุบัน
current month. So and the AI assistant automatically
AI assistant จะ
provided me the correct SQL query. And the real killer feature for me is
ให้ SQL query ที่ถูกต้องโดยอัตโนมัติ และฟีเจอร์ที่ยอดเยี่ยมสำหรับผมคือ
that Supabase actually knows all of your structure, so it really can
Supabase รู้จักโครงสร้างทั้งหมดของคุณ ดังนั้นมันจึงสามารถ
create correct queries based on your data because it knows everything
สร้าง query ที่ถูกต้องตามข้อมูลของคุณ เพราะมันรู้ทุกอย่าง
about all of your database. And you may be wondering,
เกี่ยวกับ database ของคุณทั้งหมด และคุณอาจสงสัยว่า
how am I going to use it in the code so you can ask it like to
ผมจะใช้งานมันในโค้ดอย่างไร คุณสามารถขอให้มัน
turn it into PostgreSQL function. Now you see that the I used the same
แปลงเป็น PostgreSQL function ตอนนี้คุณจะเห็นว่าผมใช้
function, but it it is now wrapped in an expression that turns it
function เดียวกัน แต่มันถูกห่อด้วย expression ที่แปลงเป็น
into a function, and the function is called like get_active_users_last_month
function และ function นั้นเรียกว่า get_active_users_last_month
It automatically provided all the types,
มันกำหนด type ทั้งหมดให้โดยอัตโนมัติ
so it returns integer as a result. And once it is available you can
ดังนั้นมันจึง return integer เป็นผลลัพธ์ และเมื่อมันพร้อมใช้งาน คุณสามารถ
call it in a in your code. So you just refer to supabase.rpc
เรียกมันในโค้ดของคุณได้ คุณเพียงแค่อ้างอิงถึง supabase.rpc
Then you specify the name of the
จากนั้นคุณระบุชื่อของ
function. And again because Supabase
function และอีกครั้ง เพราะ Supabase
generates all of the types for you here you not only have tables,
สร้าง type ทั้งหมดให้คุณ ในนี้ไม่ได้มีเพียงตารางเท่านั้น
but you also have functions. So all the functions like function
แต่มี function ต่างๆ ด้วย ดังนั้น function ทั้งหมด
signature or the correct return type, everything is going to be
signature หรือ return type ที่ถูกต้อง ทุกอย่างจะถูก
perfectly typed for TypeScript. And it's really nice.
กำหนด type อย่างสมบูรณ์ใน TypeScript และมันดีมากๆ
So I also use Supabase to store files.
ผมยังใช้ Supabase ในการจัดเก็บไฟล์ด้วย
For example, if I decide to study tie, this is how I study tie.
ตัวอย่างเช่น ถ้าผมตัดสินใจเรียนภาษาไทย นี่คือวิธีที่ผมเรียนภาษาไทย
By the way, I can create a file with voice
ผมสามารถสร้างไฟล์เสียง
that says Sawasdee Krub in Thai, and after the record is created
ที่พูดว่า "สวัสดีครับ" เป็นภาษาไทย
using OpenAI, I can store it in a database and in the Supabase.
โดยใช้ OpenAI สร้าง หลังจากนั้น ผมสามารถจัดเก็บไว้ใน Supabase ได้
So I just use storage, specify bucket ID which is like a folder for files.
ผมเพียงแค่ใช้ storage ระบุ bucket ID ซึ่งเป็นเหมือนโฟลเดอร์สำหรับไฟล์
Then I specify a file name the actual file and that's enough.
จากนั้นผมระบุชื่อไฟล์ เนื้อหาของไฟล์ และแค่นั้นก็เพียงพอแล้ว
Then you get the URL which you can attach to this card, which is like in
จากนั้นคุณจะได้รับ URL ซึ่งคุณสามารถแนบไปกับการ์ดนี้ ซึ่งใน
my case the card was somebody crap. So I can attach this voice and
กรณีของผม การ์ดคือ "สวัสดีครับ" ผมสามารถแนบเสียงนี้และ
store it in Supabase. And the final step is how to
จัดเก็บไว้ใน Supabase ขั้นตอนสุดท้ายคือวิธี
optimize database. The database optimization is
ปรับแต่ง database การ optimize database เป็น
kind of a broad topic, and I'm only going to cover indexes
หัวข้อที่กว้าง และผมจะพูดถึงเฉพาะ index
because it's a lot to cover. And when we think about how to
เพราะมันมีเยอะมาก และเมื่อเราคิดถึงวิธี
optimize database, we need to like apply basic
ปรับแต่ง database เราต้อง
patterns that we use in real life. For example, that let's say we have
นำรูปแบบพื้นฐานที่เราใช้ในชีวิตจริงมาประยุกต์ใช้ ตัวอย่างเช่น สมมติว่าเรามี
a book, we have a book, and we would like to find the word apple.
หนังสือ และเราต้องการหาคำว่า "apple"
There is someone somewhere word apple.
มีคำว่า "apple" อยู่ที่ไหนสักแห่ง
But we know that if this book is alphabetically sorted from A to Z,
แต่เรารู้ว่าถ้าหนังสือเล่มนี้เรียงตามตัวอักษรจาก A ถึง Z
the word apple should be somewhere in the very beginning.
คำว่า "apple" ควรจะอยู่ที่ไหนสักแห่งในตอนต้น
This way you can narrow down the search and save the time.
วิธีนี้คุณสามารถประหยัดเวลาในการค้นหาได้
So this is how all these indexes work in the database in this query,
นี่คือวิธีการทำงานของ index ต่างๆ ใน database query นี้
I would like to get all the cards created by specific user.
ผมต้องการหาการ์ดทั้งหมดที่สร้างโดย user ที่ระบุ
So the apple here is the user ID. So we need to create an index for
ดังนั้น "apple" ที่นี่คือ user ID เราต้องสร้าง index สำหรับ
this field and for this query. And Supabase allows us to do that.
ฟิลด์นี้และสำหรับ query นี้ และ Supabase อนุญาตให้เราทำเช่นนั้นได้
So in the dashboard you can go to to the indexes tab.
ใน dashboard คุณสามารถไปที่แท็บ indexes
And then you specify the deck and the column which you would
และจากนั้นคุณระบุตาราง deck และคอลัมน์ที่คุณต้องการ
like to be indexed. You might be wondering why not.
ให้ถูก index คุณอาจสงสัยว่าทำไม
Why can't Supabase or PostgreSQL create all the indexes by itself?
ทำไม Supabase หรือ PostgreSQL ไม่สามารถสร้าง index ทั้งหมดได้เอง
The issue is that creating index has some performance penalties.
ปัญหาคือการสร้าง index มีผลกระทบต่อประสิทธิภาพ
So like it simplifies reading. So the reading is faster.
มันทำให้การอ่านง่ายขึ้น ดังนั้นการอ่านจึงเร็วขึ้น
But when you create a lot of indexes the writing becomes slower.
แต่เมื่อคุณสร้าง index จำนวนมาก การเขียนจะช้าลง
Because let's say you have a table with ten fields and then you insert
เพราะสมมติว่าคุณมีตารางที่มี 10 ฟิลด์ แล้วคุณ insert
one record with ten indexes. And then when you create this record,
หนึ่ง record ที่มี 10 index และเมื่อคุณสร้าง record นี้
you need to. Create an indexes so it slows
คุณต้องสร้าง index ดังนั้นมันจึงทำให้การ insert ช้าลง
down the insert while speeding up the read.
ในขณะที่ทำให้การอ่านเร็วขึ้น
So that's why you need to like fully control it.
ดังนั้นคุณจึงต้องควบคุมมันเองอย่างเต็มที่
To figure out which field requires an index,
เพื่อหาว่าฟิลด์ใดต้องการ index
there is a PostgreSQL extension that is built inside Supabase and you
มี PostgreSQL extension ที่สร้างขึ้นภายใน Supabase และคุณ
can run your query that you have. It may be as complex as you wish,
สามารถรัน query ต่างๆ ที่คุณมี ซึ่งซับซ้อนได้เท่าที่คุณต้องการ
and then it shows you which fields require an index in this
และจากนั้นมันจะแสดงให้คุณเห็นว่าฟิลด์ใดต้องการ index ใน
specific query. Or instead of using CLI, you can go
query นี้ หรือแทนที่จะใช้ CLI คุณสามารถไปที่
to the indexes dashboard and see, for example, most time consuming
dashboard ของ indexes และดู query ที่ใช้เวลามากที่สุด
queries most frequent and those that have slowest execution.
query ที่พบบ่อยที่สุด และ query ที่มีการดำเนินการช้าที่สุด
So and this way it provides you the list of indexes that needs
ด้วยวิธีนี้ มันจะให้รายการ index ที่ต้อง
to be created that internally use this index advisor tool.
ถูกสร้างขึ้น ซึ่งภายในใช้เครื่องมือ index advisor
So as a summary, we learned how to create database structure via user
สรุป เราได้เรียนรู้วิธีสร้าง database structure ผ่าน
interface instead of CLI, how to automatically generate TypeScript.
user interface แทน CLI, วิธีสร้างไฟล์ TypeScript โดยอัตโนมัติ
So you don't need to manually transfer all the fields from
คุณไม่จำเป็นต้องถ่ายโอนฟิลด์ทั้งหมดจาก
your database to your code. How to write your own SQL for queries
database ของคุณไปยังโค้ดของคุณด้วยตนเอง วิธีเขียน SQL ของคุณเองสำหรับ query
and how to use AI to do it for you instead. How to upload files.
และวิธีใช้ AI เพื่อทำแทนคุณ วิธีอัปโหลดไฟล์
Because Supabase is not only a cloud platform is a full stack
เพราะ Supabase ไม่ใช่แค่ cloud platform แต่เป็น full stack
platform that can replace a team of developers and how to optimize
platform ที่สามารถแทนที่ทีมนักพัฒนา และสุดท้าย วิธีปรับแต่ง
your database when it gets larger as your project grows.
database ของคุณเมื่อมันใหญ่ขึ้นเมื่อโปรเจกต์ของคุณเติบโตขึ้น
So thank you so much for for listening to me.
ขอบคุณมากที่รับฟังผม
And in case you're interested in the project.
และในกรณีที่คุณสนใจโปรเจกต์นี้